<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kim Fitter</title>
    <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kim Fitter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0)</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kimnewzealand.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crepes made with Git</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/gitcrepeexample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/gitcrepeexample/</guid>
      <description>19 March 2018
Version control of code seems similar to creating, updating and sharing recipes. Since we were trying out crepe recipes at home, I decided to use this personal connection to work through a crepes made with git example to validate my understanding of Git from the command line.
Inspired by Reflections on 4 months of GitHub: my advice to beginners by Suzan Baert, I also started a personal Git cheatsheet, which will be incrementally updated with gems from future projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a website in Hugo creative portfolio theme</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>30 January 2018
There are a many tutorials and the great bookdown blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown with detailed steps on how to create a website using blogdown and Hugo.
I used the fantastic tutorial by Tyler Clavelle to create this blog. This website uses the blogdown R package and static site generator Hugo. I chose to use the Hugo creative portfolio theme, with side bar and tiles layout. I use Windows and GitHub repo to deploy the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello blog</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/hello/</guid>
      <description>2 January 2018
Welcome to my personal blog and portfolio of my data science journey.
Until now I have been creating and publishing R code to github and HTML to RPubs. I also have a Wordpress professional website to reach out to both technical and non-technical audiences with summaries of projects. I realised I needed another more personalised medium to publish the detailed code and HTML from projects so I created this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Blockchain Example in R</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/firstblockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/portfolio/firstblockchain/</guid>
      <description>SynopsisThis R markdown post was inspired by the R-bloggers post Building your own blockchain in R.
Blockchain technology, types such as bitcoin and ethereum and its associated terminology are ubiquitous in the media at the moment.
The objective here is to learn how a generic blockchain works and understand some of the terminology through implementing a simple example. This generic example could then extended to various types of blockchains such as distributed ledgers, smart contracts or cryptocurrencies with network servers and appropriate privacy and security settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>