<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codes on Kim Fitter</title>
    <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codes on Kim Fitter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0)</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crepes made with Git</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/gitcrepeexample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/gitcrepeexample/</guid>
      <description>19 March 2018
Version control of code seems similar to creating, updating and sharing recipes. Since we were trying out crepe recipes at home, I decided to use this personal connection to work through a crepes made with git example to validate my understanding of Git from the command line.
Inspired by Reflections on 4 months of GitHub: my advice to beginners by Suzan Baert, I also started a personal Git cheatsheet, which will be incrementally updated with gems from future projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel to Interactive Census Map</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/censusmapsexample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/censusmapsexample/</guid>
      <description>6 April 2018
I have been experimenting with spatial data and looking at ways to combine data objects to get different views and perspectives. This post has the following objectives:
Import and load data direct to R without manually saving files to a local directory, so that the end to end process is reproducible.Use vectors to efficiently clean the Excel sheet, reducing manual steps where possible so that the process could be leveraged to clean other Excel sheets in the Census data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Blockchain Example in R</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/firstblockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/code/firstblockchain/</guid>
      <description>30 January 2018
This R markdown post was inspired by the R-bloggers post Building your own blockchain in R.
Blockchain technology, types such as bitcoin and ethereum and its associated terminology are ubiquitous in the media at the moment.
The objective here is to learn how a generic blockchain works and understand some of the terminology through implementing a simple example. This generic example could then extended to various types of blockchains such as distributed ledgers, smart contracts or cryptocurrencies with network servers and appropriate privacy and security settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>