<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogdown on Kim Fitter</title>
    <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/tags/blogdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogdown on Kim Fitter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kimnewzealand.github.io/tags/blogdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Favicon in the Blackburn Theme</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2019/03/15/changing-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2019/03/15/changing-logo/</guid>
      <description>Personalised logosThe new Data Visualisation Society has created personalised logos, see the behind the scenes post by [Amy Cesal](https://twitter.com/AmyCesal.
Here is the key to the logo:
There is also a timezone overlay:
My personalised logoMy logo looks like this:
Purple I have a background in project management and I am involved in community group organisation represented by the purple triangle.
Green I am fairly comfortable in data analysis and cleaning as I spend most of my time using R represented by the green triangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Would Have Thought The Slug Was The Bug</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/12/12/structure-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/12/12/structure-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>This post is of the the folder structure of a blogdown website, to get a basic understanding of how it works and to also remind myself next time I face a similar publishing issue!
Publishing issue I have been updating my blogdown website with posts, and then I hit an issue. The about link would not update. I tried multiple amendments and multiple commits to no avail. I then re-created the whole website and reinstalled the theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Theme with Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/08/15/changing-theme-with-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/08/15/changing-theme-with-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>This blog was using the creative portfolio theme until the number of posts grew. The tiled effect became busy and the website required a different website format including an archive list.
I have changed the theme to Blackburn following this post by Mike Treglia.
So far so good&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/01/02/hello-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/01/02/hello-blog/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal blog and portfolio of my data science journey.
Until now I have been creating and publishing R code to github and HTML to RPubs. I also have a Wordpress professional website to reach out to both technical and non-technical audiences with summaries of projects. I realised I needed another more personalised medium to publish the detailed code and HTML from projects so I created this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating A Website In Hugo Creative Portfolio Theme</title>
      <link>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/01/01/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimnewzealand.github.io/2018/01/01/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>There are a many tutorials and the great bookdown blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown with detailed steps on how to create a website using blogdown and Hugo.
I used the fantastic tutorial by Tyler Clavelle to create this blog. This website uses the blogdown R package and static site generator Hugo. I chose to use the Hugo creative portfolio theme, with side bar and tiles layout. I use Windows and GitHub repo to deploy the website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>