<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Kim Fitter</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Kim Fitter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Meter Data Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/portfolio/smartmetereda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/smartmetereda/</guid>
      <description>SynopsisOn 13th December 2017 I attended a day of the IASC-ARS/68th Annual NZSA Conference. I attended a talk by Rob Hyndman on Probabilistic Outlier Detection And Visualization Of Smart Meter Data.
Inspired by Rob Hyndman’s talk, I decided to perform an exploratory data analysis of smart meter data. There are a variety of open energy data resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a website in blogdown and Hugo</title>
      <link>/portfolio/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/creating-a-website-in-blogdown-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>There are a few tutorials on how to create a website using blogdown and Hugo. This is a summary of of my tips if you are using Windows, github repo and hugo creative portfolio theme.
Once you have installed your theme, do not change any of the theme folder files. You can override these with new files in your blog_down source directory.
This theme does not seem to accept list.html in layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello blog</title>
      <link>/portfolio/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/hello/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal blog and portfolio of my data science journey.
I started coding in March 2017 and until now I have been creating and publishing R code to github and HTML to RPubs. I also have a Wordpress professional website to also reach out to both technical and non-technical audiences with summaries of projects. I realised I needed another more personalised medium to publish the detailed code and HTML from projects so I created this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>